Eastman-Goodale-Dayton Family Papers, 1861-2013
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES III. WRITINGS 1866-2001, undated, 2.25 linear ft.
  This series is arranged by individual author (Elaine's and Dora's childhood writings are filed under Elaine's name), and then by genre. The bulk of the writings in this series were authored by Elaine Goodale Eastman and Charles Eastman. Dora Goodale is also well represented. There are a handful of poems and essays by other family members, especially Deborah Hill Read Goodale. Most of the writings were published as books or in newspapers or periodicals, but there are also a few unpublished manuscripts and typescripts. Family members, especially Elaine, wrote prolifically in many genres: memoirs, novels, children's books, poetry, short stories, plays, biography, articles, essays, and letters to the editor. The oldest item is a short journal written at Sky Farm by Eleanor Rogers Lyon Read in 1866. Family members regularly contributed to national and local publications, such as The Woman's Journal, The Woman's Home Companion, The Christian Century, The New York Times, The Springfield (Massachusetts) Daily Republican, The Daily Hampshire Gazette (Northampton, Mass.), and many others. Elaine and Charles wrote about Native American life and public policy, and Elaine also addressed the topics of nature, farming, and domestic life, especially early in her career. She also contributed articles related to her organizational activities with the D.A.R., League of Women Voters, and the Northampton Motion Picture Council. Other members of the family wrote poetry and articles about nature, farming, and other subjects. SERIES VI. SCRAPBOOKS includes articles, essays, poems, reviews, and letters to the editor from magazines and newspapers.
- SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION AND SUBJECT FILES OF ELAINE G. EASTMAN 1928-53, undated, .75 linear ft.
  This series is organized alphabetically by the name of the organization or subject file. The subject matter is primarily about Native Americans, but there is also a small amount of material about the D.A.R. blacklist controversy in the late 1920s and the Women's International League for Peace and Freedom, Northampton Branch. The bulk of the material appears to have been saved by Elaine Eastman in Northampton during the 1940s and early 1950s and dates from that period.
- SERIES V. PHOTOGRAPHS 1860-1993, undated, .25 linear ft.
  This small series is organized by individual or place. Its most notable content is the series of photographs taken by Elaine at the Pine Ridge Agency in South Dakota, documenting events surrounding the Wounded Knee Massacre. Photographs of sites related to the Eastmans were taken by Keith F. Johnson in 1993.
- SERIES VI. SCRAPBOOKS 1877-1950, undated, .75 linear ft.
  There are ten scrapbooks in this series that overlap with each other in terms of subject matter and date span. Most, if not all, were apparently compiled by Elaine Goodale Eastman, who donated them. Most of the items in the scrapbooks have to do with the writings of the family, primarily Dora and Elaine, but Deborah Hill Read Goodale, Henry Goodale, and Rose Goodale Dayton are also represented. The scrapbooks have been numbered in an arbitrary manner. Two of the scrapbooks relate to ElaineÆs and DoraÆs childhood writings. There are four scrapbooks that contain mostly writings by Elaine relating to her career teaching and advocating for Native Americans, but also on other topics such as homemaking, children, and her organizational involvement. There is one scrapbook that mostly contains writings by others about Native Americans. DoraÆs post-childhood writings are collected in two of the scrapbooks. Finally, there is one scrapbook of miscellaneous writings, mostly poems, by Elaine, Dora, Rose, and their parents.
- OVERSIZE MATERIALS 1874-1952, undated, .25 linear ft.
  One box contains two folders of miscellaneous printed materials.
- SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIALS
  - Contents (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Jones Library, Amherst, MA: information about holdings related to Elaine and Charles Eastman, and Dora Goodale1975 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Eastman Family: letter from Norma Kidd Green to Margaret Grierson1967 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Goodale-Read-Dayton families: genealogy, notes about Chester Goodale, article re: Mt. Washington, Massachusetts, letter, and history by Stuart Reeve [circa 1919], 1979, 2013, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Dayton, James W.: clipping1957 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Dayton, Rose and Redington: drawing, 1886; wedding invitation, 1891; and note by Rose re: family correspondence1946 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Eastman, Charles
    - Newspaper clippings and obituary1891, 1915, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - "Charles Alexander Eastman: Sioux Storyteller and Historian," by Anna Lee Stensland, American Indian Quarterly, Vol. 3, No. 3, autumn,1977 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Eastman, Elaine Goodale
    - General: newspaper clippings, including obituary1891, 1946, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - "Child Poets" of Sky Farm: newspaper clippings1878, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Letters of introduction from Samuel C. Armstrong and W.H. Hare1889 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Wedding to Charles Eastman: newspaper clippings1891 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Song recital including "Ashes of Roses" by Goodale/Wood, Amherst, MA: program1910 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Eastman, Dora Winona: clipping re camp Oahe, circa 1916 brochure for Pahata camp in Granite, NH circa 1932 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Goodale, Dora Read
    - General: death certificate and obituary1953 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - "Reading Dora Read Goodale's Mountain Dooryards: An American History" by Jessica George, Undergraduate Honors Essay, Cornell University2009 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Uplands Sanatorium: printed materials1944, 1946, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Mensel, Eleanor Eastman: obituary1999 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Risk, Cynthia Whitbeck: obituary2009 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Whitbeck, Elaine Goodale: obituary2010 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE
  - Family
    - Cheshough, J. C. ("Uncle Collins") to Rose Goodale1890 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Dayton, James W. to Rose Goodale Dayton and Redington Dayton
      - 1909-13, undated (Box 1, Folder 22-27)
      - From Camp Oahe 6 Jul 1917 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Dayton, Marjorie Breckinridge (daughter-in-law) to Rose Dayton undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Dayton, Rose Goodale and Redington
      - Courtship letters Apr 1890-Sep 1891 (Box 2, Folder 3-8)
      - James Dayton1910 (Box 2, Folder 9-10)
    - Dayton, Rose Goodale
      - Dayton, Nell1918 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - Dayton, Theodore undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - Goodale, Henry Sterling undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
      - Goodale, Robert (about their mother's death, never sent)1910 (Box 2, Folder 14)
      - Unidentified letters to Rose
        - "Dosia" [niece of Redington Dayton?]1927-29 (Box 2, Folder 15)
        - [Goodale?], Margaret ("cousin")1958 (Box 2, Folder 16)
        - Al and Laura to "Mother Rose" 1925 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Dayton, Theodore R.
      - Dayton, James1914, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - Dayton, Rose and Redington
        - from grandparents home, and the Sanford School1904; undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
        - from Amherst College circa 1913-16 (Box 2, Folder 20)
        - from Camp William Lawrence (West Gloucester, MA)1914 (Box 2, Folder 21)
        - from Camp Oahe (Munsonville, NH) circa 1915-23, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
      - Read, Elmer1903 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Eastman, Charles ("Ohiyesa") to Rose G. Dayton1890 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Eastman, Dora Winona
      - Rose G. Dayton1942, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - Lewis, Ben, 1958 (includes letter from Lewis to Margaret Grierson) 1959 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Eastman, Elaine Goodale
      - Dayton, Redington1890, [1918?] (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Dayton, Rose G.
        - 1891-[late 1940s/early 1950s], undated (Box 3, Folder 5-6)
        - "Weak" letter from late in life, including a note from Virginia Eastman Whitbeck undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Goodale, Deborah Read circa 1904-05? (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - Goodale, Dora Read [circa 1898-99?]-1940, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Eastman, Irene
      - Dayton, Rose G.1917 (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - Goodale, Dora1917 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Eastman, Marion to Rose G. Dayton and Dora Goodale1940, 1942, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Goodale, Deborah Hill Read
      - Dayton, Rose G. and Redington1890, 1908, undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - Goodale, Henry Sterling1862 (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - Read, Ella1861-65 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Goodale, Dora Read
      - Eastman, Elaine Goodale [circa 1910], 1927, [circa late 1930s-40s] (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - Dayton, Redington1932 (Box 3, Folder 17)
      - Dayton, Rose G.
        - from Seattle circa pre-1918 (Box 3, Folder 18)
        - 1893-1942, undated (Box 3, Folder 19-21)
        - 1947, undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
        - from Uplands, Pleasant Hill, TN undated [circa 1930s] (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
        - n.d. and fragments undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - Goodale, Deborah Hill Read circa 1904-05 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Goodale, Robert1927 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Goodale, Henry Sterling
      - Dayton, Rose G.1896-1906, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - Goodale, Caroline (HSG's niece)1861 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - [Goodale?], "Aunt Mattie" to Rose G. Dayton1918 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Goodale, Robert
      - Dayton, Rose G. (re: Dora's deteriorating condition)1947, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
      - Eastman, Elaine G.1947 (Box 4, Folder 10)
      - Goodale, Dora undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Goodale, Samuel ["Uncle Sam"] to Rose G. Dayton and Elaine G. Eastman1913-15 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Mensel, Eleanor Eastman (re: Ohi's funeral) to Rose G. Dayton1940 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Read, Eleanor Lyon (from Sky Farm) to Mary [?] and Ella Read, her daughters1865-67 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Read, Ella ("Auntie") to Rose G. Dayton circa 1908 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Read, George
      - Dayton, Rose G. (her uncle)1890 (Box 4, Folder 16)
      - Read, Eleanor (her son, an I.O.U.)1852-66 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Sanford, Edith [Redington Dayton's sister?] to Rose G. Dayton1916 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - [Winton?], Sarah H. to Ella Read, and Dora Goodale,[circa 1860s], 1896 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Friends and associates
    - to Rose G. Dayton
      - [Edwards?], Charles undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
      - [Fillors?], Mrs.1902 (Box 4, Folder 21)
      - Clare [?] undated (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Dayton, Theodore from "Doug," undated (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Eastman, Elaine G.
      - General, A-Z1890, 1912, 1932-48 (Box 4, Folder 24)
      - Collier, John1941 (Box 4, Folder 25)
      - Dawes, Anna L.1936 (Box 4, Folder 26)
      - Dawes, Henry1887 (Box 4, Folder 27)
      - Eliot, Samuel A.1934-35 (Box 4, Folder 28)
      - Folsom, Cora undated (Box 4, Folder 29)
      - Grierson, Margaret Storrs1947-53 (Box 4, Folder 30)
      - King, Cora Smith1935 (Box 4, Folder 31)
      - Lindquist, G.E.E.1935-47 (Box 4, Folder 32)
      - McCaskill, J.C.1941 (Box 4, Folder 33)
      - Peabody, George Foster1929 (Box 4, Folder 34)
      - Richardson, Anna Steese1935 (Box 4, Folder 35)
      - Schwimmer, Rosika1930 (Box 4, Folder 36)
      - Vorse, Mary Heaton1936 (Box 4, Folder 37)
      - Young, Donald1933-35 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Goodale, Henry S.
      - to Mrs. Benedict undated (Box 4, Folder 39)
      - from Thomas Wentworth Higginson1877 (Box 4, Folder 40)
- SERIES III. WRITINGS
  - Dayton, Rose G.: poems1916, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Eastman, Charles
    - Books
      - From the Deep Woods to Civilization (including excerpts from Indian Boyhood), edited by A. LaVonne Brown Ruoff, Lakeside Press, R.R. Donnelley & Sons Company, Chicago; reprint of original 1916 edition 2001 (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - Indian Boyhood: published volume1902 (Box 5)
      - Red Hunters and the Animal People1904 (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - Smoky Days Wigwam Evenings, by Charles and Elaine Goodale Eastman1910 (Box 5)
      - The Soul of the Indian1911 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Article: "The Indians' Gift to the Nation," The Quarterly Journal of the Society of American Indians, Eastman, Elaine G.Jan-Mar 1915 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Childhood writings of Elaine and Dora Goodale
      - All Round the Year: published volume1881 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - Apple Blossoms1878
        - Published volumes (small and large editions with distinct bindings) (Box 6, Folder 1)
        - Letter, publisher's advertisement, and reviews1878, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - In Berkshire with the Wildflowers: Published volume1879 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - Miscellaneous verses1871-76, undated, [See also OVERSIZE MATERIALS] (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - Correspondence
        - A-Z1878-80 (Box 6, Folder 5)
        - Whiting, Charles (of the Springfield Republican) to Henry S. Goodale1878 (Box 6, Folder 6)
        - Unidentified1878, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Books
      - Hundred Maples: published volume (2 copies)1935 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - Indian Legends Retold1919 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - Journal of a Farmer's Daughter (1881): published volume and reviews1881, undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Little Brother O'Dreams: published volume1910 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - Pratt: The Red Man's Moses1935
        - Published volume (Box 7, Folder 4)
        - Publisher's advertisement undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - Sister to the Sioux: The Memoirs of Elaine Goodale Eastman
        - Published volume, edited by Kay Graber1978 (Box 7, Folder 6)
        - "Little Sister to the Sioux," typescript by E.G. Eastman. undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - Voice at Eve: published volume (2 copies)1930 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - Yellow Star: published volume1911 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Articles
      - Captain Pratt and His Work for Indian Education," Indian Rights Association April 1886 (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - "Ghost Dance War and Wounded Knee Massacre of 1890-91," Nebraska History (Jan-Mar 1945): published article, typescript, and correspondence 1945-46 (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - "Indian Life and Growth at Hampton," The Independent 11 Jun 1885 (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - "Spinner in the Sun. The Story of Helen Hunt Jackson": unpublished typescript undated, [See also OVERSIZE MATERIALS] (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Short stories
      - "The Hand-made House, Country Life in America [photocopy, issue not identified]1911 (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - "Pagan Interlude," undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
      - "A Pot of Tulips," New England Magazine July 1911 (Box 8, Folder 10)
      - "The Taming of the Bull": typescript undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Poems
      - General: published, manuscript, and typescript poems; and newspaper review of "Indian Pipes" 1886-1920, undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
      - The Coming of the Birds: published facsimile undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
      - "Ghost Dance War," n.d.: typescript undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
      - "The Indian Girl's Song": handwritten, Hampton Feb 1885 (Box 8, Folder 15)
      - Correspondence1904-10, 1939 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Plays
      - "The Eagle and the Star: A Play for Camp Fire Girls1916 (Box 8, Folder 17)
      - Unpublished typescripts undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Sheet music: "Ashes of Roses," words by Elaine Goodale, music by Mary Knight Wood1892 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Goodale, Deborah Hill Read
    - Published articles1900, 1903, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - "Mrs. and Miss Brotherton": short story typescript undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Poems
      - Published in newspapers
        - 1883-1902 (Box 9, Folder 3)
        - n.d., (alpha by title)undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - Miscellaneous manuscripts1882, 1886, 1888 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: letter from S.C. [Samuel C.] Armstrong1890 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Goodale, Dora Read
    - Books
      - Mountain Dooryards [1946?]: published volume (2 copies), publisher's advertisement, and book review1946, 1950 (Box 9, Folder 7)
      - Test of the Sky: published volume (2 copies)1926 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Articles and essays
      - Published in magazines and newspapers
        - 1897-1924 (Box 9, Folder 9)
        - undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
      - Manuscripts1926, undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Short stories
      - Published in magazines and newspapers
        - 1890-1928 (Box 9, Folder 12)
        - undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
        - Manuscripts undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Poems
      - Published in magazines and newspapers1883-1919, undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
      - Manuscripts and typescripts undated (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Note re: suicidal thoughts undated (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence (includes one letter to EGE): Sarah Cleghorn1942, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Goodale, Henry S.
    - "Does Farming Pay?," Harpers New Monthly Magazine October 1880 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - "The Blowden's Day in Berkshire": manuscript play with illustrations 1883? (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Poems: manuscripts1872, 1878, 1903, undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Read, Eleanor Rogers Lyon: original manuscript and transcription of diary excerpt re: Sky Farm1866 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION AND SUBJECT FILES OF ELAINE G. EASTMAN
  - Daughters of the American Revolution: circular letters by Eastman re: blacklist controversy1928-29 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Native Americans
    - General
      - Pamphlets1940-52, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - Magazine and newspaper articles1935-50, undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Akwesasne Mohawk Counselor Organization1951, undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - American Indian Political Advisory Committee1952 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Campfire Girls, Inc.: "Following Indian Trails" 1950 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Eastern Regional Conference of the Fellowship of Indian Workers1944 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Friends of the Middle Border (Mitchell, SD): Middle Border Bulletin1944-50 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - General Federation of Women's Clubs, Indian Welfare Committee,1948-49, undated (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Home Missions Council of North America1948, undated (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - The Indian Association of America, Inc.1951, undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Indian Rights Association (Philadelphia)1944-53, undated (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Inter-American conference on Indian Life, Cuzco, Peru1949 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Michigan Indian Foundation1951 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Native Americans in Minnesota (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - National Congress of American Indians
      - General printed materials1947-52, undated (Box 10, Folder 20)
      - Washington Bulletin1948-52 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - National Fellowship of Indian Workers: newsletter1945-51, [See also OVERSIZE MATERIALS] (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Navajo and Hopi Indians: miscellaneous printed materials1947-52, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - New Mexico Association of Indian Affairs: newsletter1949 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - South Dakota Historical Society: The Wi-iyohi (newsletter)1949-52 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Standing Rock Sioux Tribe of Indians1951 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - United States Congress
      - Speeches re: Indians in the Congressional Record1947-52 (Box 11, Folder 5)
      - Miscellaneous hearings and reports regarding Indian policy1944-45 (Box 11, Folder 6)
      - House of Representatives. Subcommittee on Indian Affairs of the Committee on Public Lands: Compilation of Material Relating to the Indians of the United States and the Territory of Alaska, Including Certain Laws and Treaties Affecting Such Indians1950 (Box 11)
    - Department of the Interior. U.S. Indian Service: publications
      - 1933, 1948, 1949-50, undated (Box 11, Folder 7-8)
      - Indian Education: newsletter1945-53 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - The Westerners: The Westerner's Brand Book1945, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Women's International League for Peace and Freedom, Massachusetts Branch1948-51 (Box 11, Folder 11)
- SERIES V. PHOTOGRAPHS
  - Dayton, Redington1893 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Dayton, Rose Sterling Goodale1889 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Dayton, Theodore undated (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Eastman, Dora Winona1959 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Eastman, Elaine Goodale1890-91, undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Eastman, Irene undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Goodale, Dora Read1908 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Goodale, Henry Sterling circa 1860, undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - South Dakota groups and scenes
    - Taken by Elaine Goodale Eastman1890-91, undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Chamberlain, White River, Pine Ridge, and Wounded Knee, SD scenes, taken by Keith F. Johnson Aug 1993 (Box 12, Folder 10)
- SERIES VI. SCRAPBOOKS
  - #1: Articles mostly about Native Americans by Elaine G. Eastman (includes small amount of correspondence)1885-1914, 1933, undated (Box 13, Folder 1-5)
  - #2: Mountain Dooryards by Dora Goodale: reviews and correspondence1941-50, undated (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - #3: Articles, book reviews, and letters to the editor about Native Americans (includes some on miscellaneous topics)1929-49, undated (Box 14)
  - #4: Columns and articles by Elaine G. Eastman about home, children, Native Americans, and the D.A.R. blacklist from various newspapers and magazines; and programs of mother's clubs1896-99, 1911, 1928-29, undated (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - #5: Childhood writings of Elaine and Dora Goodale: correspondence, reviews, publisher's advertisements, portraits of Elaine and Dora, and programs1877-81, 1897, undated (Box 15, Folder 2-5)
  - #6: Poems by Elaine Goodale Eastman "never collected in book form": correspondence, poems published in newspapers and magazines, typescript poems, portrait (lithograph), and articles about Eastman1880-1943, undated (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - #7: Books by Elaine Goodale Eastman: correspondence, reviews, articles and letters to the editor by EGE, and publisher's advertisements1910-37, undated (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - #8: Published and manuscript articles and poems, and correspondence of Deborah Read Goodale, Henry S. Goodale, Elaine G. Eastman, Dora Goodale, and Rose Goodale Dayton1873-1937, undated (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - #9: Published and manuscript poems by Dora and Elaine Goodale Eastman,articles about EGE and DRG, letter from Samuel Armstrong to Henry S. Goodale, reviews, and advertisements1878-1906, undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - #10: Articles (mostly about travel) written for The Rural New Yorker by Dora Goodale1932-35, undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
- OVERSIZE MATERIALS
  - Scrapbook #1: originals (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - "The Author of Ramona" by Elaine Goodale Eastman [unidentified periodical] [condensation of "Spinner in the Sun"] undated (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - "Epithalamium" for Alfred Edwards and Arabella Stuart Magee by Elaine Goodale Eastman: printed poem Jun 1874 (Box 17)
  - "Triennial Conference, National Fellowship of Indian Workers, American Baptist Assembly, Green Lake, Wisconsin,": flyer1952 (Box 17)